

# Abhishek Upadhyay

# DevOps Engineer

+919555144715 | abhishekupadhyay.biz@gmail.com | India

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

DevOps Engineer with around 5+ years of experience in architect/automating and optimizing mission-critical deployments over a large infrastructure. A highly adaptable, flexible professional who embraces teamwork, but also enjoys working independently having expertise in Microsoft Azure but also familiar with AWS along with that I have experience with ADO Board, ARM Templates, Jenkins, Linux, MySQL, Bash Scripting, GIT, Github and CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps.

### **TECH STACK**

Microsoft Azure	Azure DevOps, Azure Boards, App Services, VM, Logic Apps, Key Vault, Storage, Functions, SQL Databases, VNet, DNS, CDN & Migration from On-premise to Azure Cloud
AWS	VPC, EC2, ELB, RDS, S3, IAM, Lambda
Automation	ARM Templates, Ansible
CI/CD	Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Git, Docker
Scripting	Bash Scripting, Python
Monitoring & Logging	Azure Monitor, Azure App Insights, New Relic
Other Tools/Skills	AWS, VSCode, Postman, Linux



#### **EXPERIENCE**

★ Cloud Engineer (DevOps) | Adobe Systems | Noida, India Feb 2023 – Present

Adobe Inc., originally called Adobe Systems Incorporated, is an American multinational computer software company incorporated in Delaware and headquartered in San Jose, California.

Adobe Experience Manager :

Managing Clients Infrastructure and Supporting our Product.

• Technologies/Tools:

Azure, AWS, Linux, Azure DevOps, SNOW, MS Dynamics, CICD

★ Senior Associate Consultant | Infosys Ltd. | Pune, India July 2021 – Feb 2023

Infosys Limited is an Indian multinational information technology company that provides business consulting, information technology and outsourcing services. The company was founded in the city of Pune, India.

- ❖ Azure Integration Service Migration (KPMG UK):
  - Implementing the migration of On-prem Internal System to Azure Cloud using Azure Integration Service like Logic Apps, Key Vault, ARM Templates.
  - Implementing the Azure Resources using ARM Template, integrate the IaC with Azure DevOps to make the deployment of infrastructure on the cloud.
  - Looking after the implementation and delivery of all the interfaces related to the projects, which include from design documentation to implementation on Azure Cloud.
  - Technologies/Tools:

Logic Apps, Key Vault, Azure DevOps, Azure Boards, App Services, Python, Docker, ARM Templates



★ Business Technology Analyst | Deloitte Consulting | Bengaluru, India Oct 2020 – June 2021

Deloitte is a leading global provider of audit and assurance, consulting, financial advisory, risk advisory, tax, and related services. With more than 150 years of hard work and commitment to making a real difference, our organization has grown in scale and diversity—approximately 286,000 people in 150 countries and territories, providing these services—yet our shared culture remains the same. Our organization serves four out of five Fortune Global 500® companies.

- ♦ Home & Community Based Information System (MA\_HCSIS) :
  - Implementing end to end 3-Tier infrastructure on Microsoft Azure, CICD Pipelines are hosted on Azure DevOps. It includes Build of solution through Azure Build Pipelines and deployment to targeted App Service through Release pipelines.
  - I am also responsible for migration of on premise TFS 2012 server to Azure DevOps Services and changing the Version Control System from TFS to Git with full history. Apart from this I am also mentoring two juniors who had joined in as freshers. The responsibilities involved providing an in depth technical/business knowledge of the cloud, cicd pipelines and infrastructure setup.
  - <u>Technologies/Tools:</u>

Azure DevOps, Azure Boards, App Services, GIT-Tf tool, IIS Servers, Docker, AzureSQL, Jenkins, CDN, ECS, Ubuntu, Python, ARM Template

★ Software Engineer | SVAM International | Noida, India Mar 2019 – Sept 2020

SVAM International Inc. is a global Information Technology (IT) services provider that delivers value and competitive advantage to our customers with high quality, cost-effective services that improve their access to actionable information, automate their business processes, and help their personnel collaborate.

- Protrack End to end containerized infrastructure setup. CICD pipelines on Azure DevOps and test cases executed through Jenkins (Maven). Also daily tasks like database backup & server snapshots are taken.
- ❖ Brightbucks I set up infrastructure to host this website where the backend is on Azure App Service (PaaS) and also Static Website on storage account. I also set up a pipeline for build and release to App Service and Blob Storage.

Neev-Cloud - I worked on making an end to end architecture for hosting this website on AWS (VPC, EC2, S3, ELB, IAM, Lambda etc.). Pipelines for UAT and Prod environment on Jenkins with 'Pre-Deployment Mail Notification Service'. The monitoring solutions used for this project are Grafana dashboards ●

#### Technologies/Tools:

Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps, AWS, Ansible, Docker, MySQL, Jenkins, CDN, Linux, Bash, Python, IIS Server, ARM Templates

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology (CSE) | GLA University | Mathura, India 2015 – 2019

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamental (AZ-900)
- Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104)
- Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer Expert (AZ-400)